あたい 瓦版屋のお園 スクープ狙って潜入しちゃうよ
お江戸の女湯に  レッツ?ザ?ブーン
Women's Bath
I'm a journalist, Osono!
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
I'm going undercover for a scoop!
My target is the Edo Women's Bath.
Here I go!
I'm a journalist, Osono.
あたいは 瓦版屋のお園
Journalist
I'm a newspaper reporter,
みんなに熱いニュースを伝える瓦版の記者をやってるんだ
and my job is to share the hottest news.
Top Secret
Lately I've been chasing a scoop
on the Insect Magistrates
最近 狙ってるのは
お江戸を蟲から守る 蟲奉行所のスクープ
who protect Edo from insects.
Especially Tsukishima Jinbei-san!
なかでも注目は月島仁兵衛さん
Tsukishima Jinbei
But today, he's gone out to train...
だけど 仁兵衛さんは今 修行に行ってるんだって
だから 今日は 他の人から ネタを聞き出すんだ
So I'm going to ask someone else.
蟲奉行所を知る人たちが よ～く来てるっていう この女湯でね
I've come to this women's bath,
where people close to the Insect
Magistrate's Office like to bathe.
I'm Osono-chan, ace reporter,
必ず スクープをものにするよ
瓦版屋のエース このお園ちゃんが
and I'm going to get my scoop!
We'll Show You Everything!!
The Edo Women's Baths!!
【全部見せます　お江戸の女湯】
In a bath, you relax and lower your guard, right?
お風呂に入るときって 身も心も緩んじゃうよね
今日はその隙を狙って
Today, I'll find out all there is to know
みんなが驚くスクープを  根掘り葉掘り 手取り足取り 聞き出しちゃうよ
about a scoop that will surprise everyone!
I'm a genius!
あたい 天才
さぁ 最初は誰
Now, where should I start?
な なに あの桃っぷり
Look at those peaches!
I feel so small...
すごい敗北感
U-Um, excuse me...
あ あの そこのお方
えっ なに
Eh? What is it?
Don't stare at them...
そんなに見ないでください
ご ごめん ごめん
S-Sorry!
Anyway, I'm the journalist Osono.
あのさ あたい 瓦版屋のお園
Aren't you Oharu-chan, of the tea shop?
あんた 茶屋の娘の お春ちゃんだよね
Y-Yes...
は はい
スクープ その１
There's my first scoop.
お団子を毎日食べていると 桃がすごいことになる
Eat dumplings daily at the tea shop,
and your peaches will grow really large!
お団子のせいじゃありません たぶん
It isn't due to the dumplings!
Probably...
あたいね 蟲奉行所のこと 取材してるんだ
I'm trying to find out more
on the Insect Magistrate's Office.
I heard you've known Tsukishima
Jinbei-san since his arrival in Edo!
お春ちゃんって 月島仁兵衛さんが
お江戸に来たときからの知り合いなんだって
えっ ええ
Y-Yes...
仁兵衛様が津軽より 出てこられたときから
I've known him since he arrived from Tsugaru.
あの
Excuse me...
Yes?
はい
どこか お怪我でも
Are you hurt?
Thank you so much!
かたじけない
しみ入ります この甘み この優しさ
So sweet! So kind...
Allow me to introduce myself.
申し遅れました
自分は蟲奉行所のお勤めに参った 月島仁兵衛と申します
I'm Jinbei and I've come here to work
at the Insect Magistrate's Office!
My, the Insect Magistrate's?
あぁ 蟲奉行所で
はい
Yes.
My name is Haru.
私は春と申します
この茶屋の娘です
I work here at this tea shop.
Wow!
なんと
どうされました
Is something wrong?
いえ なんでも
No, nothing.
Thanks for showing me the way, too.
道案内まで かたじけない
いいんです
It's fine.
仁兵衛様はどうして蟲奉行所に
What made you decide to join
the Insect Magistrate's Office?
My father, in Tsugaru, was actually summoned.
本当は津軽にいる父が呼ばれたのです
However, my father
しかし 父は 動けぬ身
cannot travel.
ですから 自分が代わりに
So I asked to fulfill my father's duties in his stead.
お上のお勤めを果たしたいと 父に申し出たのです
It took one of the girls!
女をさらっていきやがったんだ
団子屋のお春ちゃんだよ
Oharu-chan, from the tea stand!
お春殿が
Oharu-dono?
蟲はどこへ
Where did it go?
あっちだ
That way!
Oharu-dono...
お春殿
私の両親みたいに襲われないよう
So others wouldn't be attacked,
as my parents were.
みんなを蟲から守ってくださいって
No!
It's quite common here, in Edo.
江戸ではよくある話ですから
助けに来るのが遅くなって 申し訳ございません
I'm sorry it took me so long to get here!
仁兵衛様
Jinbei-sama!
It's time.
いくぞ これが江戸での初陣
This is my first fight in Edo.
My name is Tsukishima Jinbei!
月島仁兵衛 参る
Here I come!
焦るな いつでも身は戦場に
Stay calm!
Always be ready for a fight!
常住戦陣の心構えであれ
Always be ready for a fight.
No!
Father!
おっとさん おっかさん 助けて
Mother!
Save me!
Please don't worry, Oharu-dono...
お春殿 どうかご安心ください
I will not allow these monsters to touch you!
こんな化け物ごときに 指一本 触れさせませんから
I'll be stronger than anyone.
誰よりも 強く
Even stronger than my father!
父上を超えて
死ぬまで勝つ
Keep winning until you die!
Always be ready for a fight!
常住戦陣
うんうん いい話 聞かせてもらっちゃった
What a great story...
お春ちゃん ありがとう
Thanks, Oharu-chan!
いいえ ではお先に
Not at all.
Goodbye, then.
取材は順調
This is going really well!
あっ 今度は蟲奉行所の火鉢さん
That's Hibachi-san,
of the Insect Magistrate's Office!
わぁ スタイルいいな
She's so gorgeous...
I feel so small again.
またまた 敗北感
You, there...
ちょっと そこのあんた ジロジロ見ないでよ
Stop staring.
あっ ついつい
I couldn't help myself.
You're just so cool and gorgeous, Hibachi-san.
火鉢さん スタイルよくて かっこいいから
えっ そう？
Am I?
I don't know if anyone's ever
told me that before...
そんなこと言われたの初めてかも
火鉢さん あたい 瓦版屋なんです
Hibachi-san, I'm a journalist.
蟲奉行所のこと 聞かせてもらえませんか
Can you tell me about the
Insect Magistrate's Office?
About the Magistrate's Office?
蟲奉行所のこと そうね
Let's see...
じゃあ 全員揃ったことだし
Right, since everyone's here, let's start by
まずは仁兵衛君にここの勤めを説明するね
explaining to Jinbei-kun our work here.
はい
Please!
Japan is filled with giant
insects that eat humans.
実は この日本には人さえも食らう巨大蟲がいる
今より百年前から 跋扈し始めたんだ
They first appeared about a century ago.
なぜ出現したのか どのように どこから来たのかは
Why are they here?
How did it happen?
Where did they come from?
今も調査を進めている
We are still investigating.
そして 十年前巨大蟲から江戸の人たちを守るため
And ten years ago,
the Shinnakamachi Magistrate,
or the Insect Magistrate's Office,
つくられたのがこの新中町奉行所
二つ名を蟲奉行所というんだ
was created to protect Edo from them.
我々は蟲奉行様のもと 日々蟲退治をしている
We work for the Insect Magistrate,
fighting insects every day.
ほう その蟲奉行様はどちらにいらっしゃるのです
And where is the Insect Magistrate?
I'd like to meet him!
ぜひとも ご挨拶をさせてください
その必要はないよ
That's unnecessary.
The Insect Magistrate does not
reveal himself to others.
蟲奉行様は 人にお姿をお見せにならない
新入りが会えるはずねえんだよ
No way a new kid could meet him.
私たちだって 会ったことないんだから
Even we've never met him.
Really?
なんと
ということで 仁兵衛君  わかったかな
Do you understand now, Jinbei-kun?
この江戸の泰平は キミの腕にかかってるんだよ
The peace of Edo rests on your shoulders.
そのような お言葉をいただけるとは
Those are the finest words a
Samurai could hope to hear!
武士冥利 ここに極まわれり
この月島仁兵衛 お上より賜ったこのお勤め 必ず果たしてみせます
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall fulfill the duty
appointed to me by the Shogunate!
And the man I admire more than anyone,
そして 蟲奉行所には私の憧れ 無涯さんがいるんだ
Mugai-san, works for the Insect Magistrate!
Mugai-dono's overwhelming strength
makes those behind him feel safe!
無涯殿には 後ろにいる者の不安をかき消す 圧倒的な強さがあります
あのとき自分は無涯殿を目標に歩んでいくことを決めたのです
Then and there, I decided that
I would make him my goal.
無涯さんって そういう人だよね
That's the kind of guy he is, right?
あの人みたいになりたいって 思わせてくれる
He makes you think you want to be like him.
はい
Right!
He's cool, isn't he?
かっこいいよね
はい
Yes.
すてきよね
He's wonderful, isn't he?
はい
Yes.
最高よね
He's the best, isn't he?
はい
Yes.
って なんで 私があんたと無涯さんのことで盛り上がってんの
Wait, why am I discussing
Mugai-san with you, anyway?!
ふんふん それでその蟲奉行様って どんなお方なんですか
Right, right!
Then what's the Insect Magistrate like?
I can't tell you that.
それは言えない
私たちだって ついこの間まで会ったことなかったし
We only just met, not too long ago.
ってことは 会ったんですね
So you have met them!
I guess so.
まあね
でも あんなふうに会うことになるとは 思いもしなかった
I never expected we'd meet under
those circumstances, though.
え？
Huh?
You ever hear of the Insect Hunters?
蟲狩って知ってる
蟲退治を請け負う 流浪の集団なんだけどね
They're a wandering group of mercenaries
that you can hire to fight insects.
そいつらが 蟲奉行様を襲ったの
They attacked the Magistrate.
いくぞ お前たち 復讐のときだ
Let's go, men...
It's time for revenge!
どうやら この島に不審者が忍び込んだか
It appears we have intruders on this island.
すまぬ 八丈島の命たちよ
I'm sorry to all the creatures
that live on Hachijo Island.
Wait.
待て
What is it, leader?
なんだよ リーダー ビビってんのか
Are you scared?
The insects stopped chirping.
虫が鳴きやんだ
The insects...
虫が
Poison fog.
毒霧だ
マジかよ
Seriously?
Everyone, drink your antidotes.
全員 解毒丸を飲め
行くぜ
Let's go.
The Insect Magistrate is within this poison fog.
この毒霧の奥に　蟲奉行がいる
月島　あんたどこつかんでんのよ
Tsukishima, what are you grabbing?
放しなさいよ
Let go of me.
無理です　死んでしまいます
I can't...
I'll die!
What?
何と あの霧は何でしょう
What is that fog?
知らないわよ
I don't know.
気張っていくわよ
Stay sharp.
We're the first ones here.
私達は先陣なんだから
火鉢殿　お任せください
Hibachi-dono, leave it to me!
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall do everything
この月島仁兵衛　粉骨砕身火鉢殿の足を引っ張らないよういたします
in my power to not slow you down!
だから　どこ握ってんの？！
Where are your hands?
Those are the Insect Hunters?
あの者達が蟲狩
Hydrangea Blossoms.
紫陽花玉
一々受けんのもうぜんだよ
I won't stand here and let you attack me.
爆発を蹴りの衝撃波で受けるなんて
She blocked the explosions with
the shock wave from her kicks?
This is the Insect Hunters' power,
これが蟲狩の実力だ
stupid, weird-faced girl.
ちんくしゃバカ女
W-Weird-faced?
ちん　ちんくしゃ？
You're a flat-chested four-eyes!
何を　この貧乳メガネ
You shouldn't have said that.
お前　地雷踏んだな
甲脚
Armor Kick!
I don't think I can say more than that.
これ以上のことはさすがに言えないわ
Please?!
そこを何とか
だめ
Nope.
私　もう出るね
I'm getting out.
Please wait...
待ってください
だ～め
Nope.
お願い　お願い　お願いします
Please, please, please!
八丈島に行ってからというもの
So much has happened since
I went to Hachijo Island.
慌しき日々であったな
邪魔だ　ハムシ
You're in the way, insect.
あの月島という者は　お主らの仲間ではないのか
Tsukishima isn't one of you?
何を言っていやがる
What are you talking about?
Stop moving around!
ちょこぼこと
月島流　富嶽返
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Counter!
さぁ　今のうちにお逃げください　お付の方
Run away while there's still time, Miss.
そして　蟲奉行様にお伝えください
And tell the Insect Magistrate that, together,
必ずに一緒に　江戸の空を見上げましょうと
we can look at the sky in Edo!
しかし　わらわのために月島は
He merely wished to protect me...
この者を傷つけたくないと思っていただけ
I simply didn't want to hurt him...
He must have been so very warm.
この者はさぞかし暖かかったのであろうな
I hate myself for no longer being human!
人を忘れたわが身が憎い
貴様ら　無事ここから帰れると思うなよ
You will not leave this place alive.
早く正体を現せ　黒揚羽
Show yourself for what you are, Kuroageha!
Kuroageha...
黒揚羽
I will take your puny souls...
貴様らの五分にも満たぬその魂
わらわがちりあくたに潰してくれよう
and crush them into dust.
来るぞ
Here it comes!
これが　あの野郎の力か
Is that her power?
This monster is immortal.
この化け物は不死
She was playing with us, like we were kittens.
先までは子猫とじゃれ合う程度だったのさ
そこまで分かっているならば
If you understand that much,
さっさと朽ちるがよい
then prepare for your destruction.
戒汝　蓋骨　頼むぜ
Kaina... Gaikotsu!
Do it.
Evil Insect-Slaying Blade, Insect Hunter,
「滅蟲邪刀ムシカリ」　照準よし
ready to fire.
Fire, Kaina!
撃て　戒汝
無駄なこと
It's useless.
わらわにはあらゆる攻撃が効かぬ
No attack can touch me.
Did you think that little trick would work on me?
そのような子供だまし　わらわが食らうと思うたか
The front blade made it through intact?
先端の刃だけ残っている
What is this?
何だ　これは…
What's going on?
どういうことだ　力が出ぬ
My power is fading...
The tiny red blade that pierced your chest
貴様の胸を撃った赤き小さな刃
was the Evil Insect-Slaying Blade, Insect Hunter.
名は「滅蟲邪刀ムシカリ」
どうだ　蟲奉行
Well, Insect Magistrate?
我らの憎しみを込めた刃の味は
Could you feel our hate
emanating from that blade?
It was thanks to you that I made
it back, Tsukishima Jinbei.
ここにこうして戻ってこられたのは
お前のおかげだ　月島仁兵衛
Yo...
綺麗な顔しやがって
You have such a pretty face.
喜べ
Be happy.
I'm going to rip it apart.
気の済むまでぐちゃぐちゃにしてやるよ
月島
Tsukishima!
I'm sorry...
すまぬな
I won't be able to keep my promise
江戸の空をともに見る約束
to see the Edo skies with you!
果たせそうにない
すまぬな
I'm sorry.
Promise!
約束
M-Miss...
お　お付の方
Are you okay?
ご無事ですか
T-Tsukishima?
つ　月島
蟲奉行様の元へ急ぎましょう
Let's hurry to the Insect Magistrate!
And also,
約束を
keep our promise...
果たしに
月島
Tsukishima?
力を失った今　蟲から江戸を守ることなど
With my power gone, I can no longer
protect Edo from the insects.
わらわには…
一体この身に何ができるのだろう
What am I able to do now?
よーし　下書き完成
Okay, my draft's done...
I figured you'd still be here.
やっぱりまだ入ってる
ってか　ここで書いてたの
Wait, are you writing that here?
Yeah, the research was just going so well.
取材はかどったから　つい…
そろそろ出ないと　逆上せちゃいますよ
You need to get out or you'll get sick.
Should we open a window?
窓　開けよっか
何　この瓦版
What is this?!
Wait...
ちょっと こんなの書かれたら困ります
You can't write this about me!
今すぐやぶって
Rip those up now!
瓦版が…
My papers...
Stop it!
やめて
Get back here!
Don't look!
Edo's in big trouble!
Next Time
お江戸が大ピンチです
Someone's hurt!
怪我人が
Hibachi-dono, do you have
anything to stop the bleeding?
火鉢殿　手当てに使う血止めの布は
No...
持ってないわよ
What about that white cloth you always wear?
いつも白い布をおしめじゃないですか
If you take that, I won't have underwear!
それとったら　ノーパンだから
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「蟲？！人！？謎の敵、襲来！」
Insect? Man?
Insect!? Man!?
A Mysterious Enemy Attacks!
A Mysterious Enemy Attacks.